Jackline Jebet

Software Engineer | Software Testing | Junior BA

iebet.jackline.r@gmail.com

+254 714 583 006

Nairobi, Kenya

My Portfolio

in Jackline Jebet

Jebet_Jackline

Profile

I am an experienced and certified software developer with a demonstrated history of working with a wide range of programming languages and libraries as well as software design tools, namely JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, ReactJs, SQL, PostgreSQL, Node Js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Redux, Bootstrap, Github, Git, Material UI, and Figma. My goal is to be a valuable asset in your company or organization and to work with my best initiative and flexibility to reach the company's goals, driven by enthusiasm and a high level of integrity through responsibility.

Education

2022/05 - 2022/11

Nairobi, Kenya

Software Engineering, Web Development & Computer science

Moringa School of Programming □

I was introduced to software and full-stack web development as a Moringa Tech student. I worked on variety of roles, including those of a back-end and front-end developer, a product presenter, a product documentarian, and other team responsibilities during module-based projects.

Skills:

- · Javascript · ReactJs · NodeJS · Ruby · Ruby On Rails · Html · CSS · Bootstrap · Redux
- · SQL · Postgresql · Figma · Material UI

2022/03 - 2022/05

Business Analysis

Nairobi, Kenya

Hibreed Station Inc., Canada 2

I took up Business Analysis with Hibreed which got me introduced to new skills.

Skills:

Data Management · Business Analysis · Agile · Agile Methodologies · Scrum · Data Analysis · Data Mining · Data Modeling · Data Collection · Project Management

2016/09 - 2020/12

Bsc. Agribusiness Management and Entrepreneurship

Kitui, Kenya

South Eastern Kenya University 🖸

Professional Experience

2021 – present Nairobi, Kenya

Junior Software Engineer/Business Analyst

Upwork ☑

As a freelancer at Upwork and other online platforms such as Freelance.com, I have been working as a business and data analyst. And lately, I started as a junior software developer after completing my studies at Moringa School as a software engineer student. I have great hands in the following features and skills, which have been of great use to me and to the clients:

- Software development skills, frameworks and technologies including but not limited to:
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Redux, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, and Material UI
- Strong data analysis skills, well versed in data entry, validation, mapping, transformation, and cleaning.
- Google Forms and Google spreadsheets
- Google Analytics dashboards/reports

- Dashboards/reports in Excel/Tableau
- Advanced Excel/ VLOOKUP, charts/ index
- PowerPoint, Excel, Access, open office

2019/06 – 2019/09 Eldoret, Kenya

Credit Officer Intern

Uasin Gishu County government [2]

- Registration of Saccos and cooperative societies
- Perform credit control functions, train, and give advice to clients on matters of credit and financial management.
- Preparation of reports on debtors aging and cash collections.
- Capacity building and sensitization of cooperative societies, officials and members across the county
- Receive, appraise, and forward loan application forms from different cooperative societies to the staff committee.
- Compiling statistical records of all catchment areas and classifying them
- Conduct inspections on cooperative societies and Sacco's premises in order to collect data dealing with the financial and economic analysis of the cooperatives.
- Making and receiving daily collection calls from clients.

Nairobi, Kenya

Scrum Master Volunteer

I volunteered as a scrum master for an online business (offersgalore.co.ke) on an online platform. OffersGalore is an online platform used to advertise different business offers and link them to prior business owners' platforms.

- Conduct meetings and make sure all the members have joined the meetings.
- Conduct morning or evening stand-ups to ensure that everyone has a shared understanding of what each member will be doing during the day, as well as double check if there are no impediments that can hinder the sprint goal.
- Contacting research, and Updating the platform with daily offers from different online businesses
- Gained skills on how to use project management tools such as kanban and scrum boards and Jira boards

Skills

Programming JavaScript, SQL, Ruby, ReactJs, Html, Css, Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, NodeJs, Postgresql Computer PowerPoint, Word, Excel, Access, open office PowerPoint, Word, Excel, Access, open office Data Analysis Power BI, Tableau, Excel, Vlookup Google Google Google Google Forms, Google spreadsheets Google Analytics dashboards/reports Framework and Methodologies Agile, Scrum

Certificates

- Business Analysis

 □
- Project Management ☑
- Communication Foundation ☑
- Team Work Foundations ☑

- Software Testing Certificate ☑
- Leading Yourself □
- Creating and giving Business Presentations ☑

Projects

-	
2022 – present	Personal Portfolio 🖸
	My Portfolio
	I created my own portfolio to provide my personal information and mainly highlight my
	best work as well as display my accomplishments, skills, and potential.
2022 - 2022	Movers' App ☑
	Moove.Com
	Project: Moove.com App
	Objective: To provide an easy and stress-free solution to people who want to relocate
	within Nairobi and Kenya at large.
	It entails a four-step process: plan, compare, book, and move, which makes moving and
	relocation fun and convenient for our users.
2022 - 2022	DiskComp Systems ☑
	Business Analysis Project
	DiskComp Systems was founded in September 1989 as a partnership between two
	entrepreneurs.
	Diskcomp Systems came up with the idea of the invention of microprocessor-controlled
	diskette vending machines as an effective solution to the inaccessibility of diskettes in
	boxes instead of singles to students in areas with high microcomputer usage, i.e.,
	microcomputer labs in community colleges, universities, and high schools across the
	USA and Canada.
Organizations	
2022 – present	Ruby-Supremes ☑
Nairobi, Kenya	Assistant Team Lead
Languages	

Interests

• English

• Coding

• Machine Learning

• Kiswahili

• Networking

• Athletics

References

Lorenah Mbogo, *Software Engineer/Technical Mentor*, Moringa School lorenah.mbogo@moringaschool.com

Pascal Okwundu, *Founder*, Hibreed Station Inc., Canada +234 915 288 2535

Dr. Julious Kaia Kilungo, *Dean*, Agribusiness and Agricultural Economics Jkilungo@seku.ac.ke, +254713765570